(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
MUST RE:LIVE
START: 最初から始める
LOAD: 続きから始める
MUST RE:LIVE
START: Start from the beginning
LOAD: Continue
SYSTEM: 設定を変更する
EXTRA: 新規コンテンツ用
ITEM: お知らせ
QUIT: 動画を終了する
SYSTEM: Settings
EXTRA: For new content
ITEM: News
QUIT: Exit video
「だからあたしは世界を旅している。『オンガク』を見つけるために」
"That's why I'm traveling the world. To find 'Music.'"
「そう、この世界線ではそうなのね」
"So, it's like that in this world line, isn't it?"
「だってうちは……キミのことが大好きだから！」
"Because... I love you so much!"
「わたあめは、非常食、じゃないよ〜！！」
"Watame isn't emergency food, you know~!!"
「きみを見たとき、ビビビッてきたの！！」
"When I saw you, I felt a spark!!"
「そういう時はね、ぱーっと麦ジュースを飲むに限るかな〜？」
"At times like that, there's nothing better than downing some barley juice, right~?"
「ねえ、気になるなら今からここで私といっしょにやってみる？――『ライブ』ってやつ」
"Hey, if you're curious, why not try doing it with me here and now? That thing called a 'live.'"
「君が来るのを待ってたよ。この世界に……『オンガク』を取り戻すことができる君を」
"I've been waiting for you. The one who can restore 'Music' to this world."
世界がこんな風になって、どれくらい経っただろう。
How much time has passed since the world became like this?
（どこまでも続く荒野、木々や植物に侵され、崩れた建物、砂漠に埋もれ、傾く巨大なビル群）
(An endless wasteland, buildings crumbling and overgrown with trees and plants, giant skyscrapers half-buried and tilting in the desert.)
（もうずっとずっと前に起きた最悪によって世界は滅びてしまった）
(The world was destroyed by a catastrophe that happened a long, long time ago.)
（そんな黄昏を迎えた世界で…私は失われた文明の遺物を探すことを生業としている。）
(In this world facing its twilight... I make a living searching for relics of lost civilizations.)
（浄水器や濾過器のような今でも使えるものから、使い道わかならい箱のようなもの、朽ちかけた布などなど…）
(From things that are still usable like water purifiers and filters, to mysterious boxes with unknown purposes, tattered cloth, and so on...)
（そういったものを手に入れて。旅人として日々を過ごしながら、ずっと探しているものがある）
(Acquiring such items and living my days as a traveler, there is one thing I have been searching for all along.)
（それは遥か昔にこの世界から失われてしまった…『オンガク』というもの）
(It is something that was lost from this world a long time ago... something called "Music.")
（それが何かはわからない）
(I don't know what it is.)
（どうして探そうとしているのかも…よくはわからない）
(I don't even really know why I'm trying to find it.)
（でも不思議とその響きに、惹かれるのだ）
(But strangely, I am drawn to its sound.)
（だからあたしは世界を旅している）
(That is why I travel the world.)
（答えを探して、彷徨っている）
(Searching for answers, wandering around.)
（『オンガク』を見つけるために）
(To find "Music.")
さ、今日も頑張っていくかー
Well, I'll do my best today too.
いっせーの！
Ready, set, go!
はかない鼓動 落ちる前に
Before my fleeting heartbeat falls
流れる時を追い越して
Overtaking the flowing time
駆け抜ける世界
Running through the world
LOVE.EXE
作詞・作曲：桃井はるこ
Lyrics/Composition: Haruko Momoi
いくつもの名前と
With countless names
いくつもの姿を
And countless forms
使い分けて うまく生きているけど
I use them differently and manage to live well, but...
胸の奥痛いよ
It hurts deep in my chest
音立てて軋むよ
It creaks with a sound
きっと心 命ここにあるから
Surely because my heart and life are right here
新しい明日へ
Towards a new tomorrow
今 漕ぎ出す
I start rowing now
うねりの波間に さらわれたくはない
I don't want to be swept away by the swelling waves
いっせーの！
Ready, set, go!
はかない鼓動 落ちる前に
Before my fleeting heartbeat falls
流れる時を追い越して
Overtaking the flowing time
駆け抜ける世界
Running through the world
私はいつも祈ってる
I am always praying
熱い思いをぶつけたら
If I let out my passionate feelings
奇跡さえ 起こせるから
Even miracles can happen
この景色すべては
All of this scenery
寂しさでできてる
Is made of loneliness
願うだけで すぐにそばにいられた
Just by wishing, I could be by your side instantly
あの頃の姿を
The appearance from those days
追い求め彷徨う
I wander in search of it
きっと火花 言葉ここにあるから
Surely because sparks and words are right here
懐かしい歌声
A nostalgic singing voice
今 聞こえる
I can hear it now
時空の中でも 受け取れるのはなぜ
Why can I receive it even within space-time?
通じ合う その喜びを感じたい
I want to feel the joy of connecting
場所も時間も飛び越えて
Leaping over place and time
分け合える 世界
A world we can share
音がすべてと悟ったよ
I realized that sound is everything
君をもう一度見つけたら
If I find you once more
涙さえ 輝くから
Even tears will shine
いっせーの！
Ready, set, go!
はかない鼓動 落ちる前に
Before my fleeting heartbeat falls
流れる時を追い越して
Overtaking the flowing time
駆け抜ける世界
Running through the world
通じ合う その喜びを感じたい
I want to feel the joy of connecting
場所も時間も飛び越えて
Leaping over place and time
分け合える 世界
A world we can share
音がすべてと悟ったよ
I realized that sound is everything
君をもう一度見つけたら
If I find you once more
涙さえ 輝くから
Even tears will shine
もうこの世界には、人はあまり残っていない
Not many people are left in this world anymore.
文明が崩壊して、インフラ何もかもなくなってしまったのだから、仕方ないことだと思う
Civilization collapsed, and since all infrastructure is gone, I think it's inevitable.
旅をしていると、何かに引き寄せられるように誰かと出会うことがある。こんな風に。
When you're traveling, you sometimes meet people as if you're being drawn to something. Like this.
こんにちは。
Hello.
こんにちは。あなたは？
Hello. And you?
私はAZKi。この世界の地図を作りながら、色々なところを調査する「開拓者」をしているわ。キミは？
I'm AZKi. I'm a "pioneer," surveying various places while mapping this world. And you?
あたしは旅をしてるんだ。なくなってしまった大切なものを探すために。
I'm on a journey. To find something precious that has been lost.
大切なもの？
Something precious?
うん。「音楽」を。
Yes. "Music."
ふーん。そう、この世界線ではそうなのね。でもあなたは覚えているはずだわ。
Hmm. I see, that's how it is in this timeline. But you should remember it.
ん？
Hmm?
記憶にはなくても、胸の奥の深いところに、一緒に過ごした時間、気持ちを一つにした瞬間を。だってあなたにとってそれは、とっても大事なものだったはずだから。
Even if it's not in your memories, deep within your heart, you should remember the time we spent together, the moments our feelings became one. Because for you, it must have been something very important.
完全少女論 / 作詞・作曲：北澤伸一郎
Perfect Girl Theory / Lyrics & Composition: Shinichiro Kitazawa
Ah　君が好きな服
Ah, the clothes you like
濡れたままだね
Still wet, aren't they
こんな夜だから
Because it's a night like this
響かせてMusic
Let the music resonate
お気に入りの歌は
Your favorite song
君は知らない
You don't know
君だけ知らない
Only you don't know
感情論を君に投げつけて
Throwing emotional arguments at you
傷ついたふりしてるけど
Pretending to be hurt, though
完全燃焼いつも痛いくらい
Complete combustion, always to the point of pain
もっと確かめてみる
I'll try to make more sure
全然論外だけど涙出る
Totally out of the question, but tears fall
見ないでよ酷いかもなの
Don't look at me, I might look terrible
単純だって言われたくないよ
I don't want to be told I'm simple
もっと確かめてみて
Try to make more sure
ねえ　朝が来る前に
Hey, before morning comes
連れ出してみて
Try taking me out
こんな夜だから
Because it's a night like this
鳴り止まないMusic
The music that won't stop playing
お気に入りの曲は
Your favorite tune
君は踊らない
You won't dance
君だけ踊らない
Only you won't dance
感情論で君を傷つけて
Hurting you with emotional arguments
こんな人嫌になるでしょ？
You'll come to hate someone like this, right?
純情なんて呆れるくらいに
Purity, to an amazing degree
本当似合わないけど
It really doesn't suit me, though
テンションちょっと上げて知らんぷり
Raising my tension a bit and feigning ignorance
困らせたいそんな気分よ
I'm in the mood to trouble you
単純だって言われたくないよ
I don't want to be told I'm simple
きっとわがままだけど
Surely I'm being selfish, but...
完全少女論　自分中心度
Perfect Girl Theory, degree of self-centeredness
気分上々　それでいいじゃん
Feeling great, isn't that fine?
これで不完全燃焼　無敵絶好調
With this, incomplete combustion, invincible and in top form
異常事態でしょ
It's an abnormal situation, isn't it
ほんのちょっと手を伸ばして
Just stretching out my hand a tiny bit
きっと全然気づかない
I'm sure you won't notice at all
笑うよ　朝が来たら
I'll laugh when morning comes
大丈夫　だから
It's okay, that's why...
感情論を君に投げつけて
Throwing emotional arguments at you
演じてるふりしてるけど
Pretending to be acting, though
完全燃焼いつも痛いくらい
Complete combustion, always to the point of pain
君は優しいけれど
You are kind, but...
感情論を君に投げつけて
Throwing emotional arguments at you
傷ついたふりしてるけど
Pretending to be hurt, though
完全燃焼いつも痛いくらい
Complete combustion, always to the point of pain
もっと確かめてみる
I'll try to make more sure
(さっきのは……なんだったんだろう)
(What was that just now... I wonder.)
(たくさんの人たちと、その人たちが発する熱気に包まれて、あたしはすごくワクワクしてた)
(Surrounded by so many people and the passion they emanated, I was really excited.)
(何だかすごく懐かしい感じがした……)
(It felt somehow very nostalgic...)
ねえねえ、キミ、大丈夫？
Hey there, are you okay?
え？
Eh?
なんか顔色がよくなかったからさ。
You didn't look very well.
あ、うちはミオだよ。占い師をやってる。
Ah, I'm Mio. I'm a fortune teller.
お。キミ、何かを探してるね。そう占いにでてる。
Oh. You're looking for something. It says so in your fortune.
わかるの？
You can tell?
うん。よかったら話してみて。何か力になれるかもしれないし。
Yeah. If you'd like, tell me about it. I might be able to help you.
実は……
Actually...
なるほど……キミは『オンガク』を探してるんだね。
I see... You're looking for 'Music'.
それならあそこに行ってみればいいんじゃない？
In that case, why don't you try going there?
世界の果てにあるっていう、光の塔。
The Tower of Light at the end of the world.
そこには『天使』が住んでて、やってきた人の願いを叶えてくれるんだって。
I hear an 'angel' lives there and grants the wishes of those who visit.
だからそこに行ってお願いをすれば、キミの探しものも見つかるんじゃないかな？
So if you go there and make a wish, maybe you'll find what you're looking for?
親切にありがとう、そこに行ってみることにするよ！
Thank you for your kindness. I'll give it a try!
どういたしまして。でもお礼なんていらないって。
You're welcome. But I told you, no thanks necessary.
ん？
Hm?
だってうちは……キミのことが大好きだから！
Because I... love you!
ずっとずっと前からね！
From long, long ago!
遥か　遠く
Far, far away...
続く　果てなき道
An endless road continues...
それでも　いつか
Even so, someday...
辿り　着くと信じて
Believing that I will arrive.
たとえ　今は
Even if it is now...
辛く　厳しくても
Painful and harsh...
小さな　笑顔
A tiny smile...
守る　すべて捧げて
I'll give my all to protect it.
心　重なる
Our hearts overlap...
言葉より強い絆に
Forming a bond stronger than words.
染め　上げてゆく
I will dye it...
一つになる鼓動で
With a heartbeat becoming one.
記憶　辿る
Tracing back memories...
追憶の旅　続けて
Continuing the journey of reminiscence.
あらゆる事を
Because I will accept...
受け止めるから
Everything that comes.
言葉は要らないの
No words are needed...
それは　永遠に
It will last... forever.
いつも　近く
Always close...
そばで　見ていたけど
I was watching from by your side, but...
気付かず　いても
Even if you didn't notice...
今は　遠く感じる
Now it feels so far away.
跡を　追いかけ
Chasing after the tracks...
絆から愛に変われば
If bonds turn into love...
染め　上げてゆく
I will dye it...
二人だけの秘密
A secret for just the two of us.
思いを込めた
Infused with feelings...
言葉の強さ
The strength of words.
信じて
Believe in them.
...いてる
...I'm here.
うちに秘めた時 覚悟していた
When I kept it inside, I was prepared.
未来を紡ぐために
To weave the future.
気がつけばほら
Before I knew it, look.
心に宿る
Dwell within the heart,
灯火
the flame.
小さな光 寄り添い合えば
If small lights huddle together,
そっ 未来を指して
yes, pointing to the future.
青く広がる あれは空
Spreading out blue, that is the sky.
見上げる
Looking up.
もう言葉すら いらないから
Because I don't even need words anymore,
ただ 抱きしめていて
just keep holding me.
時は 永遠に
Time is forever.
降り注ぐ雨のような歓声。
Cheers like falling rain.
その中で、煌びやかな服を着たあたしは、幸せそうな笑顔で手を振っている。
Amidst that, I, wearing glittering clothes, am waving with a happy smile.
まるで、もう一人のあたしのように。
As if it were another version of me.
世界の果てにあるという光の塔。
The Tower of Light, said to be at the edge of the world.
「オンガク」を探すために、あたしはそこを目指すことに決めた。
To find 'music', I decided to head there.
何日かかるかわからないけど、幸いなことに時間はたくさんある。
I don't know how many days it will take, but fortunately, I have plenty of time.
ただ......
But...
お腹、空いた......
I'm hungry...
あ。
Oh.
なんでわためを見てお腹を鳴らしてるの!?
Why are you growling your stomach looking at Watame!?
え、わかんないけど、なんか君を見たら急に。
Eh, I don't know, but somehow looking at you suddenly...
わためは「非常食」じゃないよ〜!
Watame is not "emergency food"~!
見逃してくれたら、代わりにわためが歌うから〜
If you let me go, Watame will sing instead~
ん？
Hmm?
歌......？
Singing...?
歌って......なに？
Singing... what's that?
え、君、歌を知らないの!?
Eh, you don't know what singing is!?
よし、じゃあわためが教えてあげるよ。歌っていうのはね〜
Alright, then Watame will teach you. Singing is, you see~
滅びてゆくこのステラ 絆をたどるストーリー
This dying Stella, a story tracing the bonds.
受け継ぐ想いが 生まれ変われますように
May the inherited feelings be reborn.
breath of stella
作詞・作曲：針原 翼
Lyrics/Composition: Harihara Tsubasa
目の前 現れた無表情は
The expressionless face that appeared before me,
誰にも 懐を見せないまま
without showing its heart to anyone.
事象が 世界を歪ませて
Events distort the world,
光が ただ眩しすぎた
the light was just too dazzling.
燦々と照りつける 荒野に残した足跡
Footprints left in the brilliantly shining wilderness.
与えられたのなら 守るものだけ
If it was given, then just things to protect.
滅びてゆくこのステラ 叶うことがないとしても
This dying Stella, even if it will never come true,
変えよう 世界を 灯してゆく
let's change the world, lighting it up.
震える手が弾いた 意味を持たない銃口を
The trembling hand snapped the meaningless muzzle.
輝く星の下 私は今息をする
Under the shining stars, I take a breath now.
それなら あなたは騙したんだ
In that case, you deceived me.
今なら
If it's now...
すべてわかってしまう
I'd understand everything.
名前を
Even if
呼んでくれていても
you were calling my name...
私に
It wasn't
届けられていなかった
reaching me.
消える日の前でただ
Just standing still before
立ち尽くして煙る灰
the day of disappearance, the smoldering ash...
命の理屈がいま
The logic of life
答えを迫る
now demands an answer.
滅びてゆくそのなかで
Within that which is perishing...
息を凝らした真夜中くらい
Like a midnight where I held my breath...
崩れた絆を
The crumbled bonds...
振り解いて
Shake them off.
お願いどうかそばにいて
Please, stay by my side.
萌芽が銃声に求めた
The sprout sought it in the gunshot.
終わりと始まりの 時のなかで
Within the time of end and beginning...
Ah...
瞳の奥に満ちた
Filled within the depths of my eyes...
剥がれかけている
Held in a heart that's
心にもつ
starting to peel away...
引き金に
The finger
かけた指
placed on the trigger...
先が示す未来を
Will pray for the future
祈るだろう
it points to.
滅びてゆくこのステラ
This perishing stella...
瞬きの数の傷
Scars numbering as many as the twinkles...
心がこのまま
Even if my heart
途絶えてしまっても
ceases to exist like this...
私の生まれた理由も
Please don't let go of the reason
手放さないでお願い
I was born...
終わりと始まりの 時のなかで
Within the time of end and beginning...
Ah...
私はここにいるよ
I am here.
何度でも確かめられるよ
I can confirm it over and over,
そこにある存在と名前を
that existence and name there...
あなたが生き抜いた世界は
The world you survived
まだ私のなかで息をする
still breathes within me.
光、光、光
Light, light, light...
その星のようなきらめきが――
That star-like twinkle...
頭に焼き付いて離れない
it's burned into my mind and won't leave.
あの子がやっていたことは なんだったんだろう？
What was it that girl was doing?
「ウタ」にって言ってたけど…… 初めて聞く言葉だ
She called it 'Song'... it's a word I've heard for the first time.
だけど「ウタ」は、あたしの心の深いところに
But that 'Song'... it definitely seeped
確かに染み込んできた……
deep into my heart...
静かだなぁ……
It's so quiet...
この世界は、ずっと静寂に包まれている
This world has been wrapped in silence for a long time.
だけどさっきのあれ――「ウタ」は、
But that thing just now... that 'Song' was
そのどれとも違った
different from any of it.
あれは、なんなんだろう……
What was that...?
あと別れ際にくれたこの頭につける道具は……
And this tool she gave me when we parted,
遺物――？
the one for my head... Is it a relic...?
確かヘッドセットって言ってた
I think she called it a headset.
これを使えば―― あたしも「ウタ」えるんだろうか
If I use this... I wonder if I can 'sing' too.
forever has gone,
today is infinity
and yesterday's dreams,
today a faint memory (Ah)
forever has gone,
today is infinity
it's time to move on,
forever has gone
Disintegration
two eyes in the face of billions of voices
I saw the flashing lights move
further in the distance
(dream was not meant to be)
and outside these walls that I have created
the sound of stars colliding
echoes in the distance
and dreams they shatter
let it break into a thousand pieces
let the wind blow it all away
dreams are fragile but our hearts grow stronger from the memories...
let it break into a thousand pieces
let the wind blow it all away
dreams are fragile but our hearts grow stronger from the memories...
renew... the light...
the dream...
forever has gone,
today is infinity
and yesterday's dreams,
today a faint memory (Ah)
forever has gone,
today is infinity
it's time to move on,
(time to move on)
forever has gone
it's time to move
(time to move on)
and outside these walls that I have created
the sound of stars colliding
echoes in the distance
and dreams they shatter
let it break into a thousand pieces
let the wind blow it all away
dreams are fragile but our hearts grow stronger from the memories...
let it break into a thousand pieces
let the wind blow it all away
dreams are fragile but our hearts grow stronger from the memories...
renew... the light... the dream...
forever has gone,
today is infinity
and yesterday's dreams,
today a faint memory (Ah)
forever has gone,
today is infinity
it's time to move on,
forever has gone
(time to move on)
it's time to move
「ウタ」を知ってから、数日が経った。
A few days have passed since I learned about "song".
（旅路は進み、ようやく光の塔がおぼろげながらに見えてくる）
(The journey continues, and at last the Tower of Light comes faintly into view.)
（だけど「オンガク」や「ウタ」について知っている人は、ほとんどいなかった）
(But there was hardly anyone who knew about "music" or "song".)
（もしかしたらあたしは、ないものねだりをしているだけなのかもしれない）
(Maybe I'm just asking for the impossible.)
（でも……新しい出会いはあった）
(But... I did have a new encounter.)
Ciaoooo! I'm Raora Panthera!
あたし、絵描きをやってるんだ！
I'm a painter!
きみを見たとき、ビビッときたの！
When I saw you, I felt a spark!
きみにはこれが似合いそう！
I think this would look good on you!
さらさらさら……っと。
Scribble scribble scribble...
はい、プレゼント！
Here, a present!
プレゼント！
Present!
はい！
Yes!
プレゼント！
Present!
これ……あたし？
Is this... me?
うん、「ステージ衣装」を着た、君の絵！
Yeah, a drawing of you wearing a "stage outfit"!
So cute……
So cute...
ちょ、ちょっとあたしには可愛すぎない？
Wait, isn't it a bit too cute for me?
そんなことないよー！
Not at all!
すっごくぴったり！
It suits you perfectly!
そ、そうかな……？
Is that so...?
きみはこの「ステージ衣装」を着て……
Wear this "stage outfit" and...
Let's sing with me!
YEAH~
The knacks of surviving in this world
are being human and being right
Everyone keeps telling me to grow up fast
And it is so tough
can't wrap my head around it
Your unfair rules
Ego trip into a loop
We do belong nowhere in this world
Yet we are surviving
Getting through anything
Stay alive
Hated ones
Naked hearts
Worthless games that never end
Found them in the darkness
in the end
何が正しくて
What is right and
何が間違っているんだ
what is wrong?
僕はただ、ここで生きてると
I just want to shout out
叫びたいだけ
that I'm alive here
I heard voices calling out my true name
I will never give up
or be swayed anymore
Nobody can stop me
This is the way I am
I'll execute you, drop dead baby!
YEAH~
Everyone wanna choose the right path only
They would seek salvation in this closed world
Filthy hands and mind never get clean again though
And it is so tough
can't wrap my head around it
Cannot turn the clock back
Cannot take a turn back
We do belong nowhere in this world
Yet we are surviving
Getting through anything
Stay alive
Missing piece
Warmth of hands
Joys and even stabbing pains
Found them in the darkness
in the end
何が正しくて
What is right and
何が間違っているんだ
what is wrong?
誰だって、ここで生きてると
Anyone is shouting out
叫んでいるのに
that they're alive here
Facing what they really want to do
They'll make it at the cost of everything
Nobody can stop me
This is the way I am
I'll execute you, drop dead baby!
YEAH~
また失って、もう嫌になって
Losing again, getting sick of it
それでも消えなくて
Even so, it doesn't disappear
その心の名をなんと言うのだろう
What would you call that name of the heart?
僕はここで今、叫んでいるんだよ
I'm shouting right here, right now
君だって、ここで同じように
You too, in the same way here
叫んでいるんだろう
must be shouting
I heard voices calling out my true name
I will never give up
or be swayed anymore
Nobody can stop me
This is the way I am
I'll execute you, drop dead baby!!
YEAH~
So, this is the way I am
「色とりどりの、かわいらしい『衣装』」
"Various, lovely 'outfits'."
（それは不思議とぴったりと身体に馴染んでいた）
(Strangely, they fit my body perfectly.)
（『衣装』を身にまとい、『ヘッドセット』をつけて、歌うあたし）
(Wearing the 'outfit', putting on the 'headset', and singing.)
（あっちのあたしと、
(The me over there,
今のあたし。どっちが本当なんだろう）
and the me now. Which one is the real me?)
そういう時はね、難しいことは忘れて
In times like these, forget the hard things
ぱーっと楽しいことをするに限るかなー
and just do something fun!
クレープを焼いたりとか、アロマで癒やされたりとか、
Whether it's making crepes, being healed by aromas,
ベリーダンスを踊ったりとかして気持ちよくなれば、
or dancing belly dance—once you start feeling good,
悩み事なんてどこかに飛んでいっちゃうものなんだよ
your worries will just fly away.
そういうものなの？
Is that how it works?
うーん、そういうものかなー。
Hmm, I guess so.
だって世の中の大体のことは、それがどう見えるかなんていうのは
Because most things in this world depend on
見る人次第なんだから
the person looking at them.
たとえばアキロゼのこの格好が、芸術的に見えるか
For example, whether Akirose's outfit looks artistic
セクシーに見えるかは、あなたたち次第、
or sexy depends on you all,
みたいにね。ふふっ
like that. Hehe.
え、あ、うん
Eh, ah, right.
そうだ！せっかくこうして出会えたんだから、
I know! Since we've met like this,
いっしょに踊ろっか？
shall we dance together?
あなたとアキロゼの二人で
Just you and Akirose.
え、でもあたし、踊ったことなんてないんだけど
Eh, but I've never danced before.
だいじょうぶだいじょうぶ。これはあなたのためだけに考えた、
It's okay, it's okay. This is a choreography I came up with
踊り子アキロゼの振り付けだから
just for you, as Akirose the dancer.
ね？
Right?
とある竜の恋の歌
Toaru Ryuu no Koi no Uta
音のない大地に
In a world without sound
恋の歌 響けば
If a love song echoes
狂いだす歯車
The gears begin to spin madly
止められぬ運命が
An unstoppable fate
はじけた
Burst forth
甦る今
Now resurrected
いにしえより古き
Older than ancient times
漠の恋
A vast love
目覚めた
Has awakened
絆を求めて
Seeking a bond
炎はほとばしる
Flames burst forth
破壊と再生
Destruction and rebirth
気高き君の呪縛
Your noble curse
透きとおる魂
A transparent soul
嘘もなく気高く
Nobly, without lies
限界も抱えて
Carrying even limits
未熟な恋もって
With an immature love
愚かさ
Foolishness
月明かり今
Moonlight now
二人照らす束の間の
Briefly illuminating the two of us
時重ねた
Time overlapping
絆の行方を
The whereabouts of the bond
両手で抱きしめた
I held it in both hands
終わりと始まり
The end and the beginning
尊き君の記憶
Your precious memory
絆を　求めて
Seeking the bond
炎は　躍る
The flames dance
破壊と　再生
Destruction and rebirth
気高き　君の　呪縛
Your noble curse
絆の　行く末を
The fate of the bond
両手で　抱きしめた
I embraced it with both hands
終わりと　始まり
The end and the beginning
尊き　君の　記憶
Your precious memory
どこか懐かしいだれかと出会う度に、頭に浮かぶ映像が鮮明になってくる。
Every time I meet someone familiar, the images in my head become clearer.
もう少しで……何かがわかりそうな気がした。
I felt like I was close... to understanding something.
それって、ライブなんじゃないかな？
Isn't that what a "live" is?
ライブ？
A live?
うん、そう、私、旅芸人だから噂で聞いたことがあるんだけど。
Yeah, that's right. I'm a traveling performer, so I've heard rumors.
音楽があった頃には、よく開催されてたんだって。
I heard they used to be held a lot back when music still existed.
ふーん。
Hmm.
（そうだ、あたしはライブをやっていたんだ——）
(That's right, I used to do lives—)
ねえ、気になるなら今からここで私といっしょにやってみる？
Hey, if you're curious, do you want to try doing one with me right here?
え？
Eh?
っていうかやろうよ！ あなたとならやってみたい！
Actually, let's do it! I want to try it with you!
「——ライブ」ってやつを！
This thing called a "live"!
とおくで
From afar
きこえる
I can hear
わたしを
Calling out
呼ぶ声
To me
あなたの
Your
涙の
Tears
理由を
The reason for
知ってた
I knew it
はずなのに
Or so I thought
乾く前に
Before they dry
枯れる前に
Before they wither
全て　捧げようと
I'll dedicate everything
あなたにだけ
Only to you
なにを求めるのか
What am I seeking?
誰を愛するのかさえ
Even whom I love
わからず
Without knowing
灰のように朽ちていく心に
In a heart decaying like ash
あなたの　かけらだけは
Only pieces of you remain
手探りでも
Even if I'm fumbling
かたちをなぞれば
If I trace the shape
長い眠りの中
In a long slumber
あなたを
Of you
夢見るでしょう
I will dream
ふたり見慣れたあの日を何度でも
Those days we saw together, over and over
夜明けは　あなたにだけ
The dawn is for you alone
空には
In the sky
もう果てがないから
Because there is no longer an end
なにを求めたのか
What was it I sought?
遠い日のわたしに今
To my self from a distant day, now
問いかけ
I ask
砕かれ色褪せ　落ちてく
Shattered, faded, falling
あの
Those
かけらたちはどこへ——
Where did those fragments go—?
手探りでも　かたちをなぞった
Even while fumbling, I traced its shape
長い夢の中で　いま
Within this long dream, now
あなたと
With you
また出会えた
I was able to meet again
ふたり願った　この瞬間を　最後まで
Until the very end of this moment we both wished for
ひろがる　青い空が
The expanding blue sky
あなたを　いつでも見てるから
Because it's always watching over you
光の塔はもう目の前に迫っていた。
The Tower of Light was already closing in before my eyes.
それにつれて、頭に浮かぶ映像はさらに鮮明になってきていた。
As I approached, the images in my mind became even clearer.
まるで夢から覚めるように。
As if waking from a dream.
まるでそれが本物であるかのように。
As if it were the real thing.
――「ライブ」をしていたあの場所が。
---That place where I was performing my "live".
･･･着いた。
...I've arrived.
ここが･･･光の塔。
So this is... the Tower of Light.
塔っていうよりも、何かの舞台みたいにも見えるな。
It looks more like some kind of stage than a tower.
似てる･･･気がする。あの、「ライブ」をやっていた場所に。
I feel... it's similar. To that place where I was doing my "live".
いらっしゃい、ライオンさん。
Welcome, Lion-san.
キミが･･･願いを叶えてくれる“天使”？
Are you... the "Angel" who will grant wishes?
うん、そう。キミが来るのを待っていたよ。
Yes, that's right. I've been waiting for you to come.
この世界に･･･「オンガク」を取り戻すことができるキミを。
For you, who can bring "music" back to this world.
音楽を？あたしが･･･？
Music? Me...?
そうだよ。
That's right.
ここに来るまでにたくさんのものを受け取ったキミは、もう、音楽が何か分かってるんじゃないかな？
Having received so many things on your way here, don't you already know what music is?
ほら、ボクと一緒に飛ぼう――
Look, let's fly together with me--
零れ落ちた　絶望の淵で　私を抱きしめてください
At the edge of spilled despair, please hold me tight
静寂に埋め尽くされ　ひとりで凍えてる
Filled with silence, freezing all alone
崩れ落ちてゆく　楽園の果てで　忘れられた祈りが響いてる
At the end of a crumbling paradise, a forgotten prayer echoes
支配する闇の中でも　枯れない愛よ目覚めよ　永遠に
Even within the governing darkness, awaken, O undying love, for eternity
無限に降るこの苦を　その指で染めてください
Please dye this infinitely falling pain with those fingers of yours
叫ぶこの心が　悲しみを愛せるように
So that this screaming heart can love the sadness
まだ見ぬあの　光の景色へ
Towards that light-filled scenery yet unseen
灯してゆく
They are lighting up
滲む幻
The blurring phantom
祝宴の鐘を
The bells of the feast
その温もり、素肌に
Until that warmth reaches
伝うまで
Into the bare skin
ほとばしる
Gushing out
嵐の中も
Even in the middle of a storm
止まない
Never-ending
愛よ目覚めよ
O love, awaken
抗えぬ願いを
The irresistible wish
その身で受け止めてください
Please receive it with your whole being
出会えた喜びに
At the joy of having met you
震えてる裸の心で
With a naked heart trembling
求めるあの
Seeking beyond
残酷の彼方へ
That cruelty
こぼれ散る涙が
The spilling tears
キラキラと風に舞う頃
When they glitter and dance in the wind
絆よ、痛みを刺し
O bond, piercing the pain
永遠に消えない
So that they may never
ように
Vanish for eternity
無限に降る孤独を
Please entrust me with
私に預けてください
The infinitely falling loneliness
呼び合えた心が
The hearts that called to each other
扉を放ち羽ばたく
Release the doors and take flight
近づくあの
Approaching that
始まりの空へ
Sky of beginnings
数時間前、露天商
A few hours ago, at a night stall
へー、この街の露天は品揃えがいいな。
Heh, the night stalls in this town have a good selection.
他では見ない珍しいものがいっぱいある。
There are lots of rare things you don't see elsewhere.
旅を続けてると、やっぱりどうしても装備品は必要になってくるからな……。
As you keep traveling, you inevitably start needing more equipment...
ちょっと覗いていこう。
Let's take a quick look.
あ、これいい。 「ブランケットインクッション」
Ah, this is nice. "Blanket-in-Cushion".
クッションになるブランケット
Blanket that turns into a cushion
ブランケットなのに袋に収納すればクッションにもなるから、
It's a blanket, but it becomes a cushion when you put it in the pouch,
これがあればどこでもひと休みできて、旅のお供にぴったりかも。
so with this, I can take a rest anywhere. It might be the perfect travel companion.
コンパクトなのにふかふかで、寝心地も良さそう。
It's compact yet fluffy, and looks comfortable to sleep on.
収納袋の絵もいい感じ。
The illustration on the pouch is also nice.
こっちは何だろう？
What's this over here?
SSRBミニウォレット
SSRB Mini Wallet
「SSRBミニウォレット」か……
The "SSRB Mini Wallet", huh...
買い物をしたり、小物を収納するのに財布は必需品なんだよね。
A wallet is a necessity for shopping or storing small items.
小銭もお札も入れられるっていうのもうれしいな。
I'm glad it can hold both coins and bills.
今使ってるのも古くなってきちゃったし、そろそろ買い替えてもいいかも。
The one I'm using now is getting old, so maybe it's time for a new one.
ブレスレット
Bracelet
お、この「ブレスレット」、かっこいい。
Oh, this "bracelet" is cool.
デザインが馴染みやすいから普段使いしやすそうだし、ライオンの加護も付いてるんだー。
The design is simple, so it looks easy to wear every day, and it even has a "Lion's Blessing".
これをつけてたら君もライオンになれるかも……なーんて。
If you wear this, maybe you can become a lion too... just kidding.
ふふ、これいいな、ヘルメット被ってる。
Hehe, this is cute, it's wearing a helmet.
SSRBぬいぐるみキーホルダー
SSRB Plushie Keyring
「SSRBぬいぐるみキーホルダー」。
The "SSRB Plushie Keyring".
つけてるだけですっごく楽しい気分になれそう。
Just having it on seems like it would put me in a great mood.
手のひらサイズのちょうどいい大きさだから、バックパックにぶら下げてもいいし、ベルトに付けるのもありかな。
It's a perfect palm-sized fit, so I could hang it on my backpack or maybe even my belt.
これも買い候補っと。
Adding this to the "to-buy" list.
どうしよう、全部欲しい……
What should I do? I want them all...
どれにするか迷う。
I can't decide which one to get.
誕生日記念フルセット
Birthday Celebration Full Set
え、これを全部まとめたセットもあるんだ？
Wait, there's even a set that includes everything?
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
しかもそれだと、トマリ先生の描き下ろしのポストカードと、直筆サイン、箔押しメッセージが特典で付いてくるのか。
And with that, it comes with a special postcard by Tomari-sensei, plus a signature and message bonus?
うーん。
Hmm.
セットでください。
I'll take the set, please.
やっとわかった気がする。
I think I finally understand.
AZKi、みお、わため。
AZKi, Mio, Watame.
ラオーラ、アキロゼ、リオーナ……
Raora, Akirose, Liona...
かなた……そしてこの舞台に向けて声援を送ってくれていたたくさんのみんな。
Kanata... and all of you who sent your cheers to this stage.
みんなから受け取ったたくさんのもの……そこに込められた想い。
The many things I received from everyone... and the feelings contained within them.
それらが集まって……「オンガク」になる。
They come together and become... "music."
新しいあたしが生まれるんだ。
A new me is being born.
うん、君ならそう言ってくれると思った。
Yeah, I thought you'd say that.
そんな君に僕から、僕たちから……最後に「曲」を送るよ。
To you, I—we—give you one last "song."
今日という素敵な日の最後を飾る……新しい獅白ぼたんの誕生を祝う、世界で一つだけの「曲」。
To mark the end of this wonderful day... a unique song to celebrate the birth of a new Shishiro Botan.
今の君なら歌えるはずだ。「オンガク」を取り戻せるはずだから。
The current you should be able to sing it. Because you can reclaim "music."
「がおってこ！」
作詞・作曲・編曲：かめりあ
"Gaotteko!"
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Camellia
がおってこ！ がおってこ！ がおってこ！ がおってこ！
Gaotteko! Gaotteko! Gaotteko! Gaotteko!
15分早起きした 奇跡的な起床記録
Woke up 15 minutes early; a miraculous record.
珍しい誇らしい朝 誰のせいでしょうか？
A rare, proud morning; I wonder whose fault it is?
きみのがおが聞こえると 気がするだけかもしれないけど
When I hear your roar—it might just be my imagination, but...
無敵になる気がして 走って走って走れんだ
I feel invincible, and I can run and run and run!
Shine on!
どこ？って迷っちゃっても
Even if I'm lost and wondering where I am...
Ride on!
合図は遠くの声
The signal is a voice from afar.
迎えに行くよ We're Lions!!
I'm coming for you! We're Lions!!
Shine on!
きみがいる世界が
The world where you exist...
Ride on!
輝く合言葉
...is our shining password.
がおっていいじゃんみんなで Everybody, say 1-2-3!!
It's okay to roar! Everyone, say 1-2-3!!
がおってこ がおってこ
Gaotteko, gaotteko!
ひとりじゃないって魔法をかけたら
Cast a magic spell that you're not alone...
がおってこ がおってこ
Gaotteko, gaotteko!
不安にだって一緒に吠えて
And let's howl at our anxieties together!
がおってこ がおってこ
Gaotteko, gaotteko!
笑顔でバフかけちゃうから
I'll buff you with a smile!
がおってこ がおってこ
Gaotteko, gaotteko!
ここがそう 私達の最高
This is it: our absolute best!
Rawr rawr!! Yeah! Rawr rawr!! Yeah! Rawr rawr!! Yeah! Rawr rawr!! Yeah!
一日一獅子 Motivation
One lion a day for motivation!
低めのやる気がお上昇
Low motivation is roaring up!
Join us my peeps! 百獣で優勝
Join us, my peeps! Victory with all the beasts!
だからがおっておきましょう
So let's keep on roaring!
靴擦れした右足が 今日のやる気を持ってった
The blister on my right foot took today's motivation away.
椅子の隅っこが小指も ついでにしばいてくれた
The corner of the chair even smashed my pinky toe.
きみのがおが聞こえると そんな日もちょっとやさしくなる
When I hear your roar, even days like that become a bit kinder.
お裾分けしたくて 踊って踊って踊ってんだ
I want to share it with you, so I'm dancing, dancing, dancing!
がおってこ がおってこ
Gaotteko, gaotteko!
ジャンプするなら今しかないし
If you're going to jump, it's now or never!
がおってこ がおってこ
Gaotteko, gaotteko!
高いトコ目指しちゃおうよ Let's go!
Let's aim for the top! Let's go!
Shine on!
「この一瞬がプレゼント」
"This moment is a gift."
Ride on!
なんて真顔じゃ言えない
I can't say that with a straight face.
だから吠えちゃうな We're Lions!!
So I'll just howl it! We're Lions!!
Shine on!
きみがいる毎日が
Every day that you're here...
Ride on!
歌う合言葉
...is a password we sing.
がおっていいじゃんみんなで Everybody, say 1-2-3!!
It's okay to roar! Everyone, say 1-2-3!!
がおってこ がおってこ
Gaotteko, gaotteko!
小声でもSay ちゃんと聴こえてる
Even if you say it softly, I can hear you clearly.
がおってこ がおってこ
Gaotteko, gaotteko!
じゃあ叫んだら未来に届く!?
If we scream, will it reach the future!?
がおってこ がおってこ
Gaotteko, gaotteko!
みんなでなら446デシベル
Together, we're 446 decibels!
がおってこ がおってこ
Gaotteko, gaotteko!
ここがそう 私達の最高
This is it: our absolute best!
Rawr rawr!! Yeah! Rawr rawr!! Yeah! Rawr rawr!! Yeah! Rawr rawr!! Yeah!
言葉にすると真っ直ぐすぎて くすぐったい胸の奥が
When I put it into words, it's too direct; it tickles deep in my chest.
だからがおってこ がおってこ
So let's gaotteko, gaotteko!
「ありがとう」のかわりを
As a substitute for "thank you"...
がおってこ がおってこ
Gaotteko, gaotteko!
ここがそう 私達の最高
This is it: our absolute best!
これ……あたしが見てる夢？
Is this... a dream I'm having?
ライブをしてるあたしの方が、今のあたしが見てる夢...?
Maybe the me performing the live is the dream current me is seeing...?
胡蝶の夢って知ってる?
Do you know the butterfly's dream?
キミの言う通り、この世界はもしかしたら、もう一人のキミが見ている夢なのかもしれないし、
As you say, this world might be a dream that another 'you' is having,
もしかしたらさっきまでキミが見ていた「ライブ」こそが、この世界のキミが見ている夢かもしれない。
or maybe the 'live' you were watching until just now is the dream 'you' in this world are having.
もしかしたらいつか訪れる未来なのかもしれないし、
Maybe it's a future that will one day arrive,
観測された違う世界線を垣間見てるだけなのかもしれない。
or maybe you're just catching a glimpse of a different observed timeline.
世界は不確定なんだよ。
The world is uncertain.
「オンガク」は、そんなたくさんの世界を繋ぐ糸みたいなもの。
'Music' is like a thread that connects all those many worlds.
数え切れないほど存在する可能性の中、それでも「オンガク」だけは、いつだってそこにあるものなの。
Among the countless possibilities, 'music' is the one thing that will always be there.
うちたちが、ぼたんのことを想う気持ちもね。
As are our feelings for you, Botan.
わため、どこにいてもぼたんちゃんのこと大好きだぁー!
Watame loves Botan-chan no matter where she is!
ぼたん先輩の絵、また描きたいなー!
I want to draw you again, Botan-senpai!
ふふ、ししろんと同じ時間をのんびり過ごすの、アキロゼはすごく好きかなー。
Hehe, AkiRose really likes spending time relaxing with Shishiron.
ぼたん先輩、いつかは私と一緒にまた歌ってほしいです!
Botan-senpai, I want you to sing with me again someday!
でも、その前に!
But before that!
せーの!
One, two!
誕生日おめでとう!
Happy Birthday!
みんな... ありがとう。
Everyone... thank you.
みんなの気持ち、贈ってくれたお祝いの言葉... 確かに受け取ったよ。
Your feelings and the congratulatory words you sent... I've definitely received them.
すごく... すごく嬉しい。
I'm so... so happy.
今ならきっと、前だけを見て走っていられる。
Now, I'm sure I can keep running while looking straight ahead.
これからも新しい世界に、
From now on, in new worlds,
まだ見たことのないたくさんの可能性に、挑戦することができる!
I can take on the challenge of many unseen possibilities!
だってここが... あたしたちの最高だから!
Because this... is our peak!
だから、この先も一緒に行こう!
So, let's keep going forward together!
次に生まれるのがどんな世界でも!
No matter what kind of world is born next!
みんなのこと、本当に本当に大好きだよ!
I really, really love you all!
（次にあたしが生まれるのは、どこなんだろう）
(I wonder where I will be born next.)
（でもそれがあたしで、どこでも大丈夫）
(But as long as it's me, anywhere is fine.)
（さよならは言わない）
(I won't say goodbye.)
（きっとあたしはこの幸せな物語を胸に、）
(I'm sure that with this happy story in my heart,)
（どこまでだって飛べるはずだから）
(I'll be able to fly anywhere.)
（――そこに「音楽」と、）
(--As long as 'music' and)
（みんなからもらった温かくて優しい想いがあれば!）
(the warm, kind thoughts I received from everyone are there!)
次の世界で、また会おう――
Let's meet again in the next world--
キミがいる世界で――!
In the world where you are--!
新しい世界に旅立つ?
Depart for a new world?
SHISHIRO BOTAN BIRTHDAY 3D LIVE
MUST RELIVE
#獅白ぼたん生誕祭2025
SHISHIRO BOTAN BIRTHDAY 3D LIVE
MUST RELIVE
#ShishiroBotanBirthdayFestival2025